fantasytennisleague.com 2018-08-17

# Privacy | Fantasy Tennis League

### PRIVACY POLICY

1\. PROTECTING PRIVACY AND APPLICATION OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY

1.1 Tennis Australia Limited (Tennis Australia) is the governing body of tennis in Australia. Tennis Australia organises a number of tennis events including, without limitation, the Australian Open and Australian Open Series events. Tennis Australia also manages and promotes various tennis programs, including without limitation, ANZ Tennis Hot Shots, Cardio Tennis and the Free Tennis Days.

1.2 In its role as the governing body of tennis in Australia, Tennis Australia is committed to the protection of your personal information in accordance with the National Privacy Principles, and from 12 March 2014, the Australian Privacy Principles, set out in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth).

1.3 In Australia, tennis programs, events and activities are implemented and conducted by a number of different tennis organisations across the country. Accordingly, Tennis Australia has developed this privacy policy to apply to each Australian Tennis Organisation (ATO) as detailed below.

1.4 For the purpose of this policy, each of the following is an ATO:

Tennis Australia,  
Member Associations, being the governing body of tennis in each Australian State and Territory known as Tennis ACT, Tennis Victoria, Tennis New South Wales, Tennis Queensland, Tennis NT, Tennis West, Tennis SA and Tennis Tasmania,  
Affiliated Organisations, being those organisations (other than Member Associations, Regional Associations and Affiliated Clubs) which are affiliated to Tennis Australia from time to time in accordance with its constitution,  
Member Affiliated Organisations, being those organisations (other than Regional Associations and Affiliated Clubs) which are members of or affiliated to Member Associations and/or Affiliated Organisations and by way of example include Tennis Umpires Australia Queensland Division Inc and Tennis Seniors New South Wales Inc.,  
Regional Associations, means those regional or metropolitan tennis associations which are members of, or affiliated to, a Member Association,  
Affiliated Clubs, being those tennis clubs which are a member of or affiliated to a Regional Association and/or Member Association,  
Tennis Australia Coach Members, being those coaches that are Tennis Australia Coach Members, if they have not chosen to adopt a separate privacy policy.  
1.5 Tennis Australia may disclose your personal information to another ATO, and ATOs may disclose your personal information to Tennis Australia or other ATOs. Each organisation will collect and use your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy.

1.6 This privacy policy describes the manner in which ATOs may collect, hold and use personal information. By providing your personal information to an ATO, you consent to its use, storage and disclosure in accordance with this privacy policy.

1.7 It is important to note that only tennis organisations that are affiliated with Tennis Australia can be an ATO. If you choose to deal with a non-affiliated tennis organisation, this privacy policy will not apply.

1.8 Tennis Australia may, from time to time, review and update this privacy policy to adapt to changing business practices, and to take into account new laws and technology. The use, storage and disclosure of all personal information held by an ATO will be governed by the most recent privacy policy, posted on the www.tennis.com.au website at http://www.tennis.com.au/privacy. Tennis Australia will notify you of any amendments by posting an updated version of the policy on this website.

2\. WHAT IS “PERSONAL INFORMATION”?

“Personal information” means information or an opinion, whether true or not, and whether recorded in a material form or not, about an identified individual or an individual who is reasonably identifiable. Personal Information collected will differ depending on the relevant ATO, and may include (but is not limited to) the kinds of personal information set out in Item 5.1.

3\. WHY IS PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED?

3.1 An ATO may collect personal information to allow it to conduct and administer its business functions and to market and provide its products and services.

4\. HOW IS PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED?

4.1 Generally, an ATO will collect personal information directly from you. You may decide to provide your personal information to an ATO for a range of different reasons.

you may be a tennis player;  
you may wish to attend a tennis activity or event;  
you may wish to purchase a ticket or a corporate hospitality package to a tennis event;  
you may attend a tennis event and elect to provide your personal information while at the event;  
you may wish to be a Tennis Australia Coach Member, ANZ Tennis Hot Shots deliverer and/or Cardio Tennis deliverer;  
you may wish to apply for employment at, or volunteer for, an ATO;  
you may wish to provide services to an ATO; or  
you may enter a competition or promotion being conducted by an ATO.  
4.2 Personal information can be collected by an ATO in a number of ways and through a number of mediums. By way of example, personal information can be collected:

when you provide your personal information, or agree to your personal information being provided via one of Tennis Australia’s websites, including without limitation http://www.tennis.com.au/, http://www.ausopen.com, http://cardiotennis.com.au/, http://hotshots.tennis.com.au/, or a website managed by another ATO (Websites).  
when you enter your personal information, or agree to your personal information being entered into one of Tennis Australia’s online IT systems including, without limitation, My Tennis, Competition Planner, Tournament Planner, and Kenexa (HR recruitment system), or a system managed by another ATO (IT Systems).  
when you email an ATO or contact an ATO by telephone or mail;  
when you engage with an ATO via social media;  
when you elect to receive tennis related newsletters or other information;  
when you enter a competition that is being conducted by, or on behalf of, an ATO;  
when you purchase tickets to a tennis event from an ATO or an authorised agent or licensee;  
when you purchase merchandise from an ATO or an authorised agent or licensee;  
when you purchase other products or services from an ATO or an authorised agent or licensee; and/or  
when you provide an ATO with information in an application or consent form, survey, feedback form or incident report.  
4.3 An ATO may collect personal information regarding a child from the parent or other ‘responsible person’ associated with that child. At times an ATO may collect personal information regarding an adult from another ‘responsible person’ associated with that adult.

4.4 An ATO may also collect and use personal information that is given to it by another ATO or a third party in the course of its business, if that collection is reasonably necessary for an ATO’s or the third party’s legitimate functions or activities. Examples of such third parties could include, without limitation, the ITF, WTA, ATP, The Australian Institute of Sport, the Australian Olympics Committee, non-affiliated tennis organisations, Tennis Australia Coach Members, schools who partake in Tennis Australia programs or Law enforcement bodies.

4.5 An ATO may, at times, collect information from publically maintained records, if that collection is reasonably necessary for the ATO’s legitimate functions or activities.

5.0 WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE COLLECTED ABOUT YOU?

5.1 The kinds of personal information that an ATO collects about you will depend on the primary purpose for which such information was collected. An ATO may collect and store various kinds of information about you in connection with its legitimate functions and activities, including, without limitation:

‘contact information’, such as your name, phone numbers, address details, email address and social media details;  
your date of birth, age, gender, tennis rankings and results;  
details of tennis programs that you have participated in and the organisations that you have participated with;  
details of a disability you may suffer, if you elect to provide that information to allow the ATO to provide you with relevant services and information;  
details of your cultural background, nationality, and language(s) spoken, if you elect to provide that information to allow the ATO to provide you with culturally sensitive information and services;  
copies of communications between an ATO and you;  
information regarding any outstanding payments owed by you to an ATO;  
other personal information provided voluntarily by you. For example, this could be information provided in response to surveys or competitions;  
payment details, if you apply for membership, purchase of goods or services from, or make other payments to, an ATO or their agents, licensees or contactors;  
details of your academic qualifications, results, professional interests, reference checks, car registration and drivers licence details (if applicable), if you apply for employment or volunteer positions with an ATO;  
background checks, including reference checks, police checks, working with children checks and completed member protection declarations and related documents. This information may be obtained and retained about you if:  
you apply for, and/or obtain employment or volunteer positions;  
you apply for and/or obtain Tennis Australia Coach Membership;  
you are proposing to, or provide certain services to an ATO;  
you apply for and/or obtain accreditation at a tennis event;  
you are a tennis player participating in one of our programs or a tennis tournament, competition or event; or  
the ATO otherwise considers it appropriate to obtain background checks in relation to you before entering into contracts, arrangements or understandings with you, or entities related to you;  
medical information and emergency contact details. For example, this information may be held about you if you are a tennis player and/or have elected to participate in fitness or sporting activities, such as cardio tennis;  
non-personally identifiable information, such as your IP address, browser type, web pages visited etc.; and/or  
other personal information that is relevant to the conduct of the ATO’s legitimate activities.  
5.2 Some of the information that you give to an ATO may be required. Other information may be optional. If you do not give an ATO some of, or all, the personal information that it requests, it may affect the ATO’s ability to communicate with you. It may also affect the ATOs ability to provide products or services to you and it may affect your ability to participate in programs conducted by an ATO or apply for employment or volunteer positions with an ATO. If it is impracticable for an ATO to deal with you in circumstances where you have not provided the information or consents that it has requested, it may decline to do so.

6.0 PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED VIA WEBSITES

6.1 An ATO will not collect any personal information about users of Websites except when they knowingly provide it or as otherwise described below.

6.2 When you visit and browse an ATO’s Website, the relevant website host may collect information for statistical, reporting and maintenance purposes.

Click Stream Data

6.3 The information collected by a Website’s website host is used to administer and improve the performance of the Website and to better understand what is of interest to you. The information may include:

the number of users visiting the Website and the number of pages viewed;  
the date, time and duration of a visit;  
the IP address of your computer; and  
the path taken through the Website.  
Cookies

6.4 Cookies are small text files that are transferred to a user’s computer hard drive by a website for the purpose of storing information about a user’s identity, browser type or website visiting patterns. Cookies may be used on our website to monitor web traffic, for example the time of visit, pages visited and some system information about the type of computer being used. We use this information to enhance the content and services offered on our website.

6.5 Cookies are sometimes also used to collect information about what pages you visit and the type of software you are using. If you access the Website or click-through an email we send you, a cookie may be downloaded onto your computer’s hard drive.

6.6 Cookies may also be used to improve the operation of a Website and to better understand what is of interest to you.

6.7 You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is sent. Each browser is different, so check the “Help” menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.

6.8 If you disable the use of cookies on your web browser or remove or reject specific cookies from our website or linked sites then you may not be able to gain access to all of the content and facilities in those websites.

Web Beacons

6.9 Web beacons are images that originate from a third party site to track visitor activities. ATOs may use web beacons to track the visiting patterns of individuals accessing a Website.

7\. HOW CAN AN ATO USE AND DISCLOSE THE PERSONAL INFORMATION IT COLLECTS ABOUT YOU?

7.1 An ATO may use and disclose your personal information for the primary purpose for which it was collected and secondary purposes related to the primary purpose. You acknowledge that such primary and secondary purposes may include, without limitation:

to verify your identity and reduce the likelihood of duplications in IT Systems and Websites;  
to complete and retain background checks;  
if you work in the tennis industry to provide prospective customers with your contact details;  
to maintain the Australian tennis rankings;  
to provide you with products or services you have requested;  
to provide you with information about relevant activities and opportunities;  
to assist other ATOs;  
to promote your business if you are a Tennis Australia Coach Member and have agreed to have your contact details listed on Tennis Australia’s Website and other promotional materials;  
to develop, run, and administer existing and new competitions, programs, activities and other events;  
to share relevant player information with the ITF, WTA, ATP, Australian Olympics Committee and other relevant bodies;  
to organise medical treatment for players;  
to administer, manage and improve the Websites and IT Systems and to provide you with access to those Websites and IT Systems, and to provide you with the functionality those Websites and IT Systems enable, such as linking to and viewing the profiles of your family connections or viewing your competition schedule in Competition Planner;  
to manage your relationship with ATOs;  
to implement and administer Tennis Australia’s National Policies, copies of which are available on Tennis Australia’s website at http://www.tennis.com.au/about-us/about-tennis-australia/policies;  
to disclose to other ATOs relevant information regarding your financial standing with an ATO, including whether or not you are a financial member;  
to disclose to an ATO’s professional advisors, including accountants, auditors and lawyers, or insurers or insurance brokers, when considered necessary or appropriate;  
to assist law enforcement bodies, when considered necessary or appropriate;  
for direct marketing communications from an ATO in relation to products, including targeted online advertisements, services, event tickets, merchandise and special offers made available by either the same or another ATO or their respective corporate partners, licensees, sponsors, suppliers and broadcasters (who may, at times be outside Australia), where you have consented to receive such communications or would reasonably expect to receive such communications, and have not requested not to receive such communications. You will be able to opt-out of direct marketing at any time if you so choose, by utilizing the unsubscribe feature on electronic marketing communications, or in the case of other direct marketing materials contacting the ATO in accordance with Item 10 below; and  
where permitted by an ATO, to enable third party corporate partners, licensees, sponsors, suppliers and broadcasters who have a relationship with an ATO (and who may, at times be outside Australia), to market and promote their products and services to you where you have consented to receive such communications or would reasonably expect to receive such communications, and have not requested not to receive such communications. You will be able to opt-out of direct marketing at any time if you so choose, by utilizing the unsubscribe feature on electronic marketing communications, or in the case of other direct marketing materials contacting the ATO in accordance with Item 10 below.  
7.2 An ATO may have contractual relationships with a number of third party suppliers and IT System administrators who assist the ATO, for example IT vendors who develop, test and maintain IT Systems and Websites or medical consultants who provide medical services at Events. At times, the third party suppliers and IT System administrators may have access to your personal information in the course of supplying products and services to the ATO. At times these third party suppliers and IT System administrators may be located outside Australia, including in the United States of America, the Netherlands and Germany. These third party suppliers and IT System administrators will be required to protect your personal information on the terms set out in their contract with the ATO. An ATO may also disclose your personal information to an international tennis organisation if you are involved in a tennis tournament sanctioned by that international tennis organisation. An example is the International Tennis Federationn, based in the United Kingdom.

7.3 An ATO will not otherwise disclose personal information without permission, unless the disclosure is:

in accordance with this Privacy Policy or any agreement with the individual; or  
required or authorised by law, including without limitation the National Privacy Principles, and from 12 March 2014, the Australian Privacy Principles, under the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth).  
8\. STORAGE AND SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

8.1 Each ATO aims to keep your personal information secure. Any personal information that is collected via a Website or which is held on an ATO’s IT System is protected by reasonable safeguards which may include firewalls and encryption.

8.2 If an ATO finds that it has no further need for your personal information it may remove it from its IT Systems and destroy all record of it.

9\. HOW TO CORRECT AND ACCESS PERSONAL INFORMATION

9.1 If you provided your personal information via an IT System or Website, you can update your personal information in that IT System or Website at any time by logging onto the relevant IT System or Website and submitting the updated information. Alternatively you can contact an ATO in accordance with Item 10 to request that they update the personal information they hold about you.

9.2 You may be entitled to access personal information that an ATO holds about you. You can request access to the personal information by contacting that ATO in accordance with Item 10. The ATO may charge a reasonable fee where access is provided. There may be some legal or administrative reasons to deny access. If an ATO refuses your request to access your personal information, it will provide you with reasons for the refusal.

10\. WHO TO CONTACT ABOUT PRIVACY MATTERS

Each ATO is responsible for protecting the personal information that it holds about you in accordance with this privacy policy. If you have any queries you should contact the relevant responsible ATO directly.

If you would like to access the personal information that Tennis Australia or an ATO holds about you, have a complaint or would like further information about this privacy policy, you can contact Tennis Australia’s privacy officer either:

by email to: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection); or  
by writing to: Privacy Officer, Tennis Australia, Private Bag 6060 Richmond Victoria 3121 Australia.  
Tennis Australia will investigate your queries and complaints within a reasonable period of time and will notify you of the outcome of our investigation. Tennis Australia may refer your correspondence to the relevant ATO.
